Guide to the Commencement Addresses Delivered at the University of Pittsburgh, 1823-1970 UA.0.10.5.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Commencement Addresses Delivered at the University of Pittsburgh
1823-1970
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Chancellor
UA.0.10.5.1
0.4 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection consists of scattered holdings of the commencement addresses delivered at graduation ceremonies at the University of Pittsburgh, including its forerunner the Western University of Pennsylvania, between 1823-1970. Digital reproductions of portions of the collection are available online.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of scattered holdings of the commencement addresses delivered at graduation ceremonies at the University of Pittsburgh, including its forerunner the Western University of Pennsylvania, between 1823-1970.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the Chancellor's Office.
Arrangement
The folders in this collection are arranged in chronological order.
Previous Citation
Commencement Addresses Delivered at the University of Pittsburgh, 1823-1970, UA.0.10.5.1, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Commencement ceremonies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Baccalaureate addresses; University of Pittsburgh
- Bruce, Robert, June 27, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content Notes
  Called the first Commencement of the Western University of Pennsylvania, four years after the granting of of the Charter of 1819.
- Upfold, George, August 9, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- McConaghy, R.H., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Duff, John Milton, March 22, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Valedictory Address to the Graduating Class of the Western Pennsylvania Medical College Delivered at the Alving Theatre, Pittsburgh.
- Pepper, George Wharton, July 12, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Barnes, Julius H., June 13, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5a)
- Mayo, William J., June 11, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Pound, Roscoe, June 9, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mansbridge, Albert, May 27, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7a)
- Thorpe, Merle, February 10, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Huggins, R.R., June 7, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8a)
  An Address to the Class of 1930, School of Medicine
- MacArthur, Douglas, June 8, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Meighen, Arthur, June 14, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Elliott, Edward C. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Trueblood, David Elton, February 5, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Scharfe, Howard C. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Crawford, Stanton C., September 8, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Rusk, Dean, June 10, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Gustavson, R.G., June 9, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Larson, Arthur, August 25, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16a)
- Bishop Thomas, February 18, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Masoner, Paul H., August 31, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Hatcher, Harlan, June 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Excerpt only
- Pelletier, Lawrence L., February 3, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Heald, Henry T., June 13, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18a)
- Murphy, Robert, June 12, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Malott, Deane W., June 11, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Weeks, Edward, June 10, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Herter, Christian A. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Blake, Eugene Carson, June 10, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Taylor, Maxwell, June 11, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Webb, James E., June 3, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mumford, L. Quincy, June 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Stever, H. Guyford, June 6, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Kurtzman, David H., May 31, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Schafer, Raymond, May 29, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Gould, Samuel B., April 26, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Whitman, Marina, April 29, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Thornburgh, Richard L. (Dick), April 29, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Starzl, Thomas E., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- O'Neill, Paul, April 27, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 34)